SHANNON DUKES

Beginning Software Engineer/Accounts Receivables Specialist

1012 Green Oak Dr. #12 Novato, CA 94949 707-971-0574 mrs.knit.wit.dukes@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm a nerd for technology and gaming as well as for all things science, but I also love numbers in general. Not only do I have experience in multiple fields, but I am also going to school to develop new skills and love to learn new things. I'm a friendly person who enjoys meeting new people and working with others, but above all I want to find that forever-job that really works hard for me the way I work hard for it. I'm never afraid of a challenge and will always be excited to explore new information as it develops!

SKILLS

- Aloha systems / TSheets / CoConstruct / MS Navision / MS Business Central / IBS / Kronos / QuickBooks
- Excel / Sheets
- Word / Docs
- PowerPoint / Slides
- Outlook / Gmail / Dropbox / Drive
- Explorer / Firefox / Chrome / Safari / Edge
- Adobe Reader / Acrobat
- AP/AR
- Advertising / Merchandising
- Business Management / Coaching / Staff Development / Recruiting
- Credit Reporting
- Customer Service / Reception/Data Entry / Cash Handling
- Event Planning
- General Ledger / Item Journals / GL Accounting
- Inventory Control / Auditing / Pricing
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript / Python / Bootstrap / OOP / SQL & MySQL / MongoDB / Mongoose / ExpressJS / APIs / ORM / RegEx knowledge / Handlebars / JQuery / Dotenv / Inquirer / Pure CSS / GraphQL / NodeJS / MERN Stack / React / Apollo GraphQL / Heroku / JAWSDB / Javascript

EXPERIENCE

Straus Family Creamery, Petaluma, CA - ACCOUNTS RECEIVABLES SPECIALIST

01/2019 to Current

- Processing incoming check, ACH, wire and credit card payments from customers and Farmer's Market transactions into our accounting system.
- Using Business Central and Navision systems.
- Working with production, orders and warehouse departments to ensure paperwork and inventory accuracy.
- Assisting with monthly inventory.
- Processing month end reporting.
- Tracking all AR including slow payments, Farmer's Market cash transaction logs, payment plans for past due items, customer returns and general invoicing.
- Assisting with customer returns and courtesy/customer service credits.
- Customer outreach for past due items on account and payment assistance issues.
- Assessing and processing deductions on payments received with the assistance of the Sales and Marketing department.

G Family Construction Inc, San Rafael, CA - ACCOUNTING CLERK

01/2018 to 01/2019

- Managing the accounts payable and accounts receivable for all four companies controlled by G Family (G Family Inc, G Landscape LLC, G Electric LLC, G Design LLC).
- Preparing billing for G Electric and G Landscape on a regular basis, sending out all maintenance billing monthly for G Landscape.
- Answering phones for G Electric Maintaining all intercompany charges for subcontracting work between the companies, making all payments to vendors, performing bank transfers when necessary.
- Assisting in maintaining all external property files for the owners when necessary.
- Assistance with system implementation, office coordination, event planning assistance Sales tax payments and recording through QuickBooks.
- All overflow of basic office duties or needs.
- Matching bank feeds daily.
- Auditing all unclassified items in the chart of accounts and classing as needed, working closely with the hired CFO to maintain the chart of accounts and set up new accounts as needed.
- Assisting hired CFO with GL accounting and all GL moves necessary for the upkeep of the chart of accounts.

Chrisad Inc, San Rafael, CA - ACCOUNTING CLERK

01/2016 to 01/2018

Checking incoming accounting emails and processing requests from sales teams.

- Preparing the payment sheet from the previous day's sales as well as the daily production report and growth report.
- Distributing invoices.
- Processing daily accounts receivables orders.
- Updating client files.
- Processing billing each month as well as collection calls on delinquent accounts.
- Processed new client agreements.
- Closing out daily charges.
- Following up on pending items with sales teams.
- Auditing statements each month.
- Creating and sending out collection and website deactivation letters for delinquent accounts.
- Sending invoices and ledgers to clients when requested.
- Coding credit card statements for processing.
- Entering accounts payables items using general ledger strings.
- Matching invoices processed for clients to invoices received from vendors for verification.

Floortex Design of San Rafael, San Rafael, CA - ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

01/2015 to 01/2016

- Answering phones
- Faxing, filing, photocopying, scanning Invoicing and bookkeeping
- General cleanliness of showroom and upkeep
- Private labeling samples
- Tracking shipments
- Tracking projects with clients
- Checking in and checking out samples
- Merchandising of showroom tile department
- Greeting clients and referring them accordingly to sales team members
- Collaborating with admin at alternative showroom for invoicing and client referrals
- Interacting with reps from product lines we represent
- Assisting with pricing and sales where necessary
- Pulling dropped line items from sample collections.

Nordstrom Ebar, Corte Madera, CA - ASSISTANT DEPARTMENT MANAGER

01/2013 to 01/2015

- Visual merchandising
- Training and recruiting new team members
- Coaching team members
- Making business decisions (product procurement, new item promotion etc)
- Advertising and promotion
- Managing and reporting cost of sales
- Accounting and bookkeeping
- Small business management.

Peet's Coffee And Tea, Petaluma, CA - SHIFT LEAD

01/2010 to 01/2013

- Coaching store cleanliness
- Stocking Organization
- Training new employees
- Cash handling/counting
- Supply ordering
- Managing staff on shift
- Inventory control
- Ensuring store policy as well as health and safety standards.

EDUCATION

Casa Grande High School, Petaluma, CA - General Education

09/2000 to 06/2003

Left Casa Grande early to complete high school education doing independent study so I could also work a full time job at the same time.

Valley Oaks School, Petaluma, CA - High School Diploma

09/2003 to 09/2004

Completed my high school education doing independent study and working full time.

UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, CA - Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

06/2021 to 11/2021

Currently enrolled in a full stack coding bootcamp to be concluded in November 2021. Also studying in my off time using web based programs and applications including Mimo and Programming Hub.

AWARDS

- Web Development certificate through Mimo application received 7/5/2021.
 - This curriculum provides the understanding of the core concepts of programming using Javascript, the HTML knowledge required to create web pages and the ability to style pages using CSS.
 - It also includes the practical experience needed to combine these technologies and publish a website on the internet.
- ExpressJS certificate through Programming Hub application received 10/15/2021
 - This certifies that I have successfully completed the course of and have knowledge of ExpressJS.
- SQL certificate through Programming Hub application received 10/12/2021
 - This certifies that I have successfully completed the course of and have knowledge of SQL.

- MongoDB certificate through Programming Hub application received 10/15/2021
 - This certifies that I have successfully completed the course of and have knowledge of MongoDB.
- Published in the Immortal Verses Series from Powtry.com in 2006 for my poem "As I Stare"
- Served the homeless with Food Not Bombs in Santa Rosa.
- Crochet for the homeless while on public transit.
- Teach knitting and crochet.

LINKS

- www.linkedin.com/in/shannon-d-a9b518213
- Skype: Live:.cid.f343c012891f4631
- https://github.com/ShannonDukes